<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Blogging for income tax, company law and business services</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:15:03 +0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:15:03 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Arbitration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The essence of arbitration is that it is an agreement between two or more parties to try to resolve a dispute outside of the court system. The parties agree upon a third party as an arbitrator who will act as a judge and jury. After giving the parties the opportunity to present their side of the story and to present any relevant documents or other evidence, the arbitrator will act as King Solomon to decide who wins and who loses. 
There are usually no set rules as to how arbitration is conducted. It is typically left to the agreement of the parties. To facilitate the process, though, the parties will oftentimes agree to use the rules of an established organization like the American Arbitration Association. 
There can be binding and non-binding arbitration. A “binding” arbitration generally means that the winning party can take an arbitration award to a court of law and enforce it if the losing party does not comply with the terms of the decision. 
“Non-binding” arbitration refers to a situation where the parties agree to use arbitration as a forum to try to resolve their differences, but neither party is bound to comply with any decision by the arbitrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-of-the-benefits-of-arbitration&quot;&gt;WHAT ARE SOME OF THE BENEFITS OF ARBITRATION?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number-one benefit of arbitration is that it serves as a forum to resolve disputes outside of the judicial system. Arbitration can be fast, quick and easy, whereas lawsuits can drag on for years and years. Since the rules of evidence and procedure are usually relaxed in arbitration proceedings, the parties are also in a better position to represent themselves without having to get lawyers involved. 
It naturally follows that arbitration also tends to be less expensive than pursuing a lawsuit. While the parties will usually end up having to pay the arbitrator, his or her fees will inevitably be less than the attorneys’ fees that they may have to pay to take the same case to trial.
Even in non-binding arbitration, a benefit can be that it serves to bridge the gap in an adversarial proceeding so that the parties can get a better glimpse of where things are headed if they are unable to resolve their differences. Most cases settle, but many times it is not until the parties are “on the courthouse steps.” Non-binding arbitration may help to facilitate a settlement sooner rather than later.
Another good thing about arbitration is that an arbitrator is typically not bound by the strict rules of procedure in reaching a decision. He or she can consider a lot more facts and circumstances than a judge or jury. Arbitrators typically try to be practical and oftentimes look at compromise as being inherently fair. Thus, the likelihood is that an arbitrator’s decision will award something to at least one of the parties. However, you would not expect that damages would be awarded that were anywhere near what a jury might have awarded if (and that is a big if) the matter were to have been tried before a jury. 
Arbitration can also bring finality. Sometimes for the better, a decision on a binding arbitration cannot be appealed or overturned in the absence of a showing of extraordinary circumstances (for example, fraud, bias or other inappropriate actions on the part of the arbitrator). Thus, once a decision is rendered, the case is over. The losing party will typically not be able to appeal (which can make the matter drag on for years and years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-of-the-drawbacks-of-arbitration&quot;&gt;What are some of the drawbacks of arbitration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no guarantees that arbitration will be a fair process. As noted, once a decision is rendered in a binding arbitration, the parties are generally stuck with that decision. Without the right to appeal, there is always the risk of being subject to the whims and prejudices of the arbitrator. Overall, this is probably the biggest drawback to the arbitration process. 
Identifying other drawbacks will typically depend upon which side of the fence you are on. For example, if a party were concerned about a large jury verdict in the event a dispute ever arose, that party would negotiate for an arbitration clause so as to keep things out of court if a dispute happens to arise. For example, in view of the potential for a large jury verdict on a wrongful termination case, this might explain why an employer would want an arbitration clause in an employment contract. Given the potential for a large jury award on a malpractice action, this would also help to explain why a medical provider would want a patient to sign an arbitration clause.
Ironically enough, the rationale for having an arbitration clause in the first place may actually encourage parties to fight about something where a dispute otherwise could have been avoided. In the absence of an arbitration clause, the parties may be more inclined to compromise rather than pursue an expensive lawsuit. If arbitration is an option, though, there may not be the same deterrents and the parties may simply elect to fight about something rather than try to work out their differences more informally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions-to-ask-yourself&quot;&gt;Questions to Ask Yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-an-arbitration-clause-being-proposed&quot;&gt;Why is an arbitration clause being proposed?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are being asked to sign a contract, always look to see if there is an arbitration clause. If there is enough at stake in the contract, you should question why it makes sense to have such a clause in there. If the potential benefits outweigh the potential drawbacks, it would make sense to agree to arbitration. Otherwise, you may want to propose that it be taken out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-personal-rights-involved&quot;&gt;Are personal rights involved?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a strictly business or consumer situation, arbitration may make a lot of sense. However, it may be a different situation where other rights are involved that could potentially have a devastating effect on you personally in the event of a dispute. Examples would include anything having to do with your job or with professional services that might be rendered to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;am-i-in-the-position-to-negotiate-with-respect-to-the-arbitration-clause&quot;&gt;Am I in the position to negotiate with respect to the arbitration clause?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, all contracts are negotiable. However, the practical ability to do so depends on the bargaining position of the parties. If you are a consumer, for example, you may not have much choice other than to “take it or leave it” in many contracts that you are being asked to sign. In other situations, such as buying a house or negotiating an employment contract, you may have a large say in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;would-you-benefit-from-arbitration&quot;&gt;Would you benefit from arbitration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you have to pull out your crystal ball. Try to anticipate the nature of any disputes that would arise. Would you want to resolve them quickly and easily through arbitration with the associated risks (for example, the potential for limited damages, no right to appeal, the difficulty of assessing the fairness of the process)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;would-i-be-in-a-better-position-to-fight-a-court-battle-than-the-other-side&quot;&gt;Would I be in a better position to fight a court battle than the other side?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is sort of a ruthless way to look at the situation. In a business deal, though, you may not want to give the other side a right to arbitrate if you would be in a better position to stick it out in a court battle. The flip side, of course, is that you may very well want to agree to arbitration if your best chance at resolving any disputes that arise is going to be through getting to arbitration as quickly and inexpensively as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-i-have-to-lose-by-agreeing-to-arbitration&quot;&gt;What do I have to lose by agreeing to arbitration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this question depends upon the nature of the dispute that might arise and what your remedy might be. If you are giving up an opportunity to go to court on an injury where a large jury verdict might result in your favor, you may not want to agree to arbitration. Even though the cost of going to court would be tremendous, attorneys are more inclined to take cases on a contingency-fee basis where jury verdicts can be obtained. Primary examples would include personal injury and employment law matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-the-arbitration-clause-cover&quot;&gt;What does the arbitration clause cover?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arbitration clauses have evolved to be rather sophisticated and complex. You should read each sentence carefully and try to understand it. Sometimes the concept of arbitration may make sense but the clause itself can be too overbearing. The opposite may likewise be true. If the clause does not make sense to you, you may want to hire a lawyer to go over it with you prior to your signing the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/09/19/what-is-arbitration.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/09/19/what-is-arbitration.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Policy Support to Corporate Social Responsibilty</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses without addressing the needs and expectations of stakeholders in a community cannot remain competitive in the contemporary era. A strategic approach to Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) can bring benefits in terms of building reputation, brand value, customer relationships, operational risk management,  driving  up efficiency,  access to new markets  and better  human resource management through employee motivation and retention. Responsible business conduct is especially important when private sector operators provide public services. CSR offers a set of values on which a more cohesive society can be built and on which the transition to a sustainable financial and economic system can be based. Enhancing CSR as a means for poverty reduction and sustainable development in a developing country like ours with modest resources requires joint initiatives by all stakeholder  groups  involved:  governmental  bodies,  NGOs,  and corporations,  as  well  as  primary  producers  and  workers.  Only through co- operation of stakeholders at all levels CSR can have a beneficial social and developmental impact.  Moreover, multi-stakeholder initiatives are  an appropriate tool for experience-sharing and the development of best practices for creating a link between corporate insight and the government agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;roles-and-challenges-of-government-bodies&quot;&gt;Roles and Challenges of Government Bodies:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSR policy in theory is supposed to function as a built-in, self-regulating mechanism, whereas in practice, CSR will thrive in the context of a consistently applied and enforced set of minimum environmental and social standards only through the right mix of policies from government bodies.
Governments are expected to play four key roles:  mandating  (legislative), facilitating  guidelines  on  content,  fiscal  and  funding  mechanisms,  creating  framework conditions), partnering (engagement in multi-stakeholder  processes, stimulating dialogue) and endorsing (publicity). Throughout these roles, they can switch  gears  as  they  deem  appropriate,  between  soft  incentives  and  hard regulation.
Forms of legal incentives can range from private and voluntary codes, to certification and labeling schemes to transparency or reporting guidelines. Legal incentives as appealing as they may sound often lack the legitimacy and enforcement mechanisms of tougher law. On the other hand, the problem with the regulatory or hard approach is that, the private sector may switch to a box- ticking or compliance mode without genuine commitment or concrete substance, gradually  compromising  the  voluntary  character  of  CSR,  one  of  its  defining features. The central challenge for governments’  progression is the question of how to more effectively manage the costs and benefits of business activity and to foster business engagement in national policy processes. In other words, governments  need  to  identify  various  forms  of  intervention  that  can  more effectively  harness  the  strengths  of  the  private  sector  and  can  also  foster alignment between CSR strategies and the pursuit of overall public policy goals.
The real challenge is to deploy the right types of soft/hard incentives and cross- sector partnerships  that serve the public interest; and to create a stimulating and enabling environment for businesses to create long-term added social value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-developing-country-governments-should-be-interested-in-csr&quot;&gt;Why developing country governments should be interested in CSR:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two broad sets of justifications for public sector actors in middle and low-income countries to be engaged with CSR. One is defensive and other one is proactive.  But  these  two  are  not  mutually  exclusive.  A  policy  initiative  that initially  has a defensive  justification  may  quickly  become  part  of a proactive strategy of engagement.
The defensive justification relates to minimizing the potential adverse effects of CSR  on  local  communities,  environments  and  markets  when  it  is  imposed through  international  supply  chains  and  investment.  For increasing  domestic public benefits of CSR practices in economic, social and environmental terms, the engagement of public sector actors in CSR activities provides the proactive justification.
From  a  sustainable  development  perspective,  public  sector  engagement  with CSR  potentially  spans  social,  economic  and  environmental  spheres,  including issues of corruption,  poverty reduction  and human rights. The goals of public sector  engagement  in CSR  are likely  to differ  from  country  to country.  They might be structured in relation to the underlying drivers for public engagement in CSR.
In a tax system, a Government may promote CSR, amongst others, by the adoption of environment-friendly  tax policies, such as taxes on consumption of fossil fuels or on polluting processes and reliefs for socially desirable expenditure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;income-tax-regulation-in-bangladesh-on-csr&quot;&gt;Income Tax Regulation in Bangladesh on CSR:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National  Board of Revenue (NBR) of Bangladesh  issued Statutory  Regulatory Order (SRO) by providing tax exemption on the expenditure made by corporates for  CSR  activities  in  2011.  The  regulations  stated  in that  SRO  were  further amended  in  2012  and  the area of CSR applicable for tax exemption  was enhanced.  The rules of tax exemption for CSR activities of corporates are mentioned below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any company  will get exemption  of Income  Tax at the rate of 10% for actual cost/money expended in Corporate Social Responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conditions for Income Tax Exemptions-
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It will not be applicable for the amount expended in excess of 20% of gross income of the company or BDT 8 (eight) crore whichever is lower.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The companies which are interested to attain tax exemption facility as corporate entity, they-
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;have to pay salary-allowance of their employee-staffs regularly and must have waste treatment plant in their factory/industry especially if industrial goods are manufactured.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;must pay income tax, VAT, duty and repay institutional debt/obligations regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;can donate to the institutions under CSR only approved by Government.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;must comply with all regulations of Bangladesh Labor Act, 2006.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;cannot  treat  the  amount  expended  under  CSR  as  an  accredited expenses  in  Manufacturing  Account,  Commercial  Account  or  Profit- Loss Account.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;have to submit necessary documents/evidences  for claiming the tax exemption on CSR to the concerned Deputy Tax Commissioner.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;have to submit CSR Work Plan by the company to NBR in written for availing Income Tax Exemption Certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fields/Sectors of CSR applicable for tax exemption&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid  through  any  government  body  for  reducing  mass  crisis  in natural  disaster  (Hurricane,  Tremor,  Cyclone  and Flood)  affected area.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to organizations establishing and operating old homes.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to any social organization pursuing welfare activities for mentally and physically challenged persons.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to education institutions operating for teaching rootless children.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to organizations pursuing housing projects for slam dwellers.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to social organizations pursuing women empowerment and anti- dowry campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid  to  organizations  pursuing  subsistence  and  rehabilitation  of orphan and rootless children.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to organizations involved in independence war related research, recovery and expanding of independence  war spirit and honorable living of freedom fighters.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to organizations involved in healthy sanitation activities Hilly Chittagong, Char region and River Eroded regions.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to institutions providing medical treatment to cleft lip, cataract and cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid  to  people  and  organization  involved  in  medical  treatment activities of acid victims.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to hospitals providing free medical services to poor patients and specialized hospital improving medical treatment like cancer, liver and kidney diseases, thalassemia, ophthalmology, cardiology etc.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to public universities.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to government affiliated educational institutions in order to provide scholarship or financial aid to children of poor freedom fighter including poor brilliant students for technical or vocational education.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to government or MPO listed non-government educational institutions to set up laboratory for computer or IT training or English language training.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to institute providing technical or vocational training to unskilled or semi-skilled labors for manpower export.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to institute providing sports training or development services at national level.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to museum (built or under construction) for preserving memory of independence war.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to any institution at national level involved in preserving memory of the father of the nation.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to the fund formed under Prime Minister’s Education Assistance Trust Act, 2012&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to non profitable and non government voluntary social welfare organization working for operating rehabilitation center for medical treatment and awareness building on HIV, AIDS and Narcotics.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Aid to non profitable and non government voluntary social welfare organization    working   for   operating   rehabilitation    center   for recovered children and women from trafficking.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;csr-activities-of-banks-in-bangladesh&quot;&gt;CSR activities of banks in Bangladesh:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the banking sector of Bangladesh has been amply participating in various social activities especially, in the areas of education, health, sports, benevolent activities like donations to different charitable organizations, to poor people  and  religious  institutions,  city  beautification  and  patronizing  art  &amp;amp; culture, etc.In   June   2008,   Bangladesh   Bank   issued   a   comprehensive   circular   titled
‘Mainstreaming Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) in banks and financial institutions in Bangladesh’. In that circular, CSR was defined as (i) considering the   economic,   social   and   environmental   consequences   of   a   business,   (ii) mitigating the negative impacts and bolstering the benign effects, (iii) initiating action programs and community investments to trim down social exclusion and inequality  as well  as to address  the core sustainable  development  challenges (fulfilling  the  requirements  of  the  current  generation  without  cramping  the capacity of future generations is a generally agreed meaning of ‘sustainable development’).
BB has been motivating  banks to expand lending to the under-served  sectors both as business case and CSR obligation; expecting to lead to more broad-based inclusive growth, and therefore reduce poverty. BB has indicated some priority areas  in the field  of CSR  like Self-employment  and SME  credits  designed  to create  productive   new  on-farm/off-farm   employment;   Financing   of  biomass processing  plants,  solar  panels,  waste  recycling  plants,  Effluent  Treatment Plants  (ETPs);  Credit  programs  for  diversified  production  of  crops,  oilseeds, spices, vegetables, fruits etc.; Mobile phone based/MFI supported programs for prompt delivery of remittances; card based/mobile phone based delivery of financial services; Financing programs to promote domestic tourism and markets in cultural products/events.
Bangladesh Bank has, of course, started guiding the banking sector to become more environmentally responsive (e.g. via refinancing new loan products on solar energy, bio-gas, effluent treatment plant etc). All the commercial banks are asked to formulate their own CSR policy with the annual outlay for CSR programs and include  the  CSR  programs  in  their  mainstream  banking  activities  instead  of short-term social works like providing grants, aids and donations. In December 2010, Bangladesh Bank instructed the banks to establish separate CSR desk to
pay special attention on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting of the CSR initiatives by banks was suggested as appendage to regular annual financial reports, ultimately to build up full length wide-ranging reports in the Green Reporting  Initiatives  (GRI) format. Alike the statutory  financial reports, the CSR reports were also anticipated to be publicly available for stakeholders’ perusal.
Bangladesh Bank has been publishing CSR review report annually for tracing advancement  in  mainstreaming  of  CSR  activities.  CSR  initiatives  of  banks during last five years continued focus on i) financial inclusion of less privileged population segments and underserved  economic sectors, ii) emergency relief in humanitarian distresses, ii) promotion of health, education and cultural/recreational  activities  for  advancement  and  well  being  of underprivileged  population  segments,  iii)  financing  and  promotion  of environment friendly projects, iv) adoption of energy efficient, carbon footprint reducing internal processes and practices in own offices and establishments.
Besides CSR initiatives involving direct expenditure, financial inclusion initiatives of banks proceeded apace during last five years. All banks participated actively in promotion of lending to SMEs and agricultural. For broader, deeper financial inclusion, banks proceeded ahead on multiple fronts including increased rural bank branch presence, mobile phone banking,  and opening  of bank accounts for low income population free of charge with nominal Taka 10 initial deposit.
In 2013, CSR expenditure of banks totaled 4.42 billion taka; eight times larger than in 2009. It will not be an overstatement to say that the banking sector led
CSR initiatives in Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, banks pursue CSR practices from self initiative. Central bank usually doesn’t intervene in their CSR activities or provide any directives to motivate banks for participating in CSR activities. But, in case of Bangladesh, the central bank provided regulatory framework to banks for CSR activities and monitors that in a regular fashion. Bangladesh Bank is one of the members of United Nations Global Compact(UNGC) concentrating  in  the  areas  of  human rights, labor standards, the environment and  anti- corruption.
Bangladesh  Bank being the chair of the Steering Committee  of UNGC Bangladesh  Local Network is actively leading CSR issues and implementation  of CSR activities in financial sector as well as facilitates social investments in Bangladesh.
Bangladesh  Bank  in  association  with  CSR  Centre,  Bangladesh  playing  a  major  role  in different programs involving social, economic and environmental aspects.
Bangladesh Bank Disaster Management and Corporate Social Responsibility Fund of Taka 5 Crore has been established in BB where 2.29 crore has already been disbursed for different projects addressing health, education, environment, disaster management and Human Resources Development/Capacity Building.As Bangladesh is a developing country, both central bank and revenue collector of government  have to take proactive steps for fostering growth and economic development.   Moreover,   in  a  country   like  Bangladesh,   poverty   alleviation through minimizing income disparity is one of the top priorities. In that context, BB  devises  supervisory  policies  in  such  a manner,  especially  for  last  several years, so that banks not only move forward for their own growth, but also can
support the development initiatives of the government. On the other hand, NBR too has provided tax incentive on CSR activities aimed towards motivating sustainable development activities.
Since the issuance of CSR directive by BB and SRO on after tax incentive from NBR, the involvement of banks in CSR activities has augmented in many folded aspects.   Banks’   rapidly   increasing   participation   in   CSR   activities   with incorporation   of   socially   and   environmentally   accountable   organizational objectives,   strategies   and  operations   that  are  swiftly   turning   into   global standards   in   “socially   responsible   competition”   towards   rearing   inclusive economic and social growth and facilitate the nation to go forward with desired growth and efficient allocation of resources. Surely the collaborative effort by the concerned government bodies will further increase the CSR activities by banks which will support sustainable development drive of the Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/08/22/policy-support-to-corporate-social-responsibilty.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/08/22/policy-support-to-corporate-social-responsibilty.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/powerful-things-markdown-editor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/powerful-things-markdown-editor.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/first-mass-produced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/first-mass-produced.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/education.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/education.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accumulated experience of social living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/acumulated-experience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/06/12/acumulated-experience.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Bundler</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt; installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundler&lt;/code&gt; is a gem that manages other Ruby gems. It makes sure your gems and gem versions are compatible, and that you have all necessary dependencies each gem requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; files inform &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; about the gem requirements in your site. If your site doesn’t have these Gemfiles, you can omit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt; and just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; uses the gems and versions as specified in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; to ensure your Jekyll site builds with no compatibility or dependency conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; in your Jekyll project, this tutorial should provide answers to the most common questions and explain how to get up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/income-tax/2018/05/12/about-bundler.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/income-tax/2018/05/12/about-bundler.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We all wait for summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/we-all-wait-for-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/we-all-wait-for-summer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tree of Codes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/tree-of-codes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/tree-of-codes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Red Riding Hood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/red-riding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/company-law/income-tax/2018/01/12/red-riding.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company-law</category>
        
        <category>income-tax</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
